[rock music]
- It's hard to believe that just a few months ago
- 很难相信就在几个月前
we were petrified about starting a new school.
我们还对开始新学校感到恐惧。
- And now look at us.
- 现在看看我们。
We get to hang out with friends
我们可以和朋友一起闲逛
and dig in the dirt for a grade.
为了成绩在泥土里挖掘。
- Wait, there's grades in here?
- 等等，这里有成绩吗？
I hope I find an A.
我希望我能找到一个A。
No, I'm kidding. I know there's no A's in here.
不，我开玩笑的。我知道这里没有A。
I'll settle for a B.
我会满足于一个B。
- Who knew school could feel so un-school-ish?
- 谁知道学校可以感觉如此不学校？
- It really did work out great.
- 这真的运作得很好。
I mean, it took us three months,
我的意思是，我们花了三个月，
but we finally made a bunch of new friends
但我们终于交了一群新朋友
and everybody's happy.
而且每个人都很开心。
- Sups haps. I dig it here.
- 超级棒。我喜欢这里。
[bell rings]
[铃声响起]
- School's over already?
- 学校已经结束了？
all: Aww.
所有人: 哎呀。
- Don't worry. We get to come back to school tomorrow.
- 别担心。我们明天还可以回学校。
all: Yay!
大家：耶！
- But it's our turn to clean up.
- 但轮到我们打扫了。
all: Lucky.
大家：幸运。
- All right, see you guys tomorrow.
- 好吧，明天见，各位。
all: Bye.
大家：再见。
Hey, my shovel's stuck on a root.
嘿，我的铲子卡在树根上了。
Could you give me a hand?
你能帮我一下吗？
- Do it yourself!
- 自己搞定吧！
Is what I would have said at our old school.
这就是我在我们以前的学校会说的话。
But now, come on, guys.
但现在，来吧，伙计们。
Let's help Dickitydoo.
让我们帮帮Dickitydoo。
- Look at us.
- 看看我们。
The Harper Quads working together.
四个Harper兄弟一起工作。
Has life ever been this good?
生活有过这么好吗？
[together] Nope.
[一起] 没有。
[creaking]
[吱嘎声]
- It wasn't a root, it's a pipe!
- 那不是树根，是管子！
- We struck oil! We're gonna be rich!
- 我们挖到石油了！我们要发财了！
- No! Dickitydont!
- 不！Dickitydont！
- That's not oil. That's sewage!
- 那不是石油。那是污水！
- What? - It's Dickitydoody!
- 什么？ - 是迪克提多迪！
all: Gross!
所有人: 恶心！
- Quick! We need to plug the hole!
- 快！我们需要堵住洞口！
- Your gloves! Everybody throw your gloves in there!
- 你的手套！大家把手套扔进去！
- [exhales]
- [呼气]
There.
好了。
That should hold it.
应该能撑住。
- Great. Let's just fill this with dirt, and no one
- 很好。我们用土填满这里，这样就没人
will ever know that something terrible happened here.
会知道这里发生过什么可怕的事情。
- Hey kids, something terrible's happening at your school!
- 嘿，孩子们，你们学校发生了可怕的事情！
- I'm here at Rothschild Prep
我正在罗斯柴尔德预科学校
where investigators are still trying to figure out
调查人员仍在试图弄清楚
just what caused a sewage backup
究竟是什么导致了
that flooded the entire school.
整个学校的下水道堵塞
- I wonder what happened.
我想知道发生了什么。
- How would we know?
我们怎么会知道？
- Don't worry, kids, it's-- it's not like a giant sinkhole
别担心，孩子们，这不是——不是像一个巨大的天坑
is swallowing up your entire school.
正在吞噬你们的整个学校。
- A giant sinkhole is swallowing up the entire schoo!
一个巨大的天坑正在吞噬整个学校！
The good news is, it was already evacuated--
好消息是，学校已经疏散了——
[smash] Oh, there goes the gym!
哦，体育馆没了！
And the cafeteria, and oh, the humanities department!
还有食堂，哦，人文系也没了！
[sighs] Just think of all the kids who spent months
想想那些花了好几个月时间交新朋友、努力适应环境的孩子们吧。
making new friends and learning to fit in.
哦，这里有两个。
Oh, here's a couple of them now.
孩子们，你们对此有什么感受？
Kids, how do you feel about all this?
- 糟透了。我们得在一个新学校重新开始。
- Terrible. We're going to have to start all over again
- 一切都不会再和以前一样了。
at a new school.
- 嘿，那两个孩子看起来就像梅和迈尔斯。
- Nothing will ever be the same again.
有些事情会完全保持不变。
- Hey, those kids look just like Mae and Miles.
[欢快的音乐]
- Some things will stay exactly the same.
有些事情会完全保持不变。
[upbeat music]
- ♪♪
[whistling]
♪ ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪ - ♪ Hey! ♪
♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪ - ♪ 嘿！ ♪
♪ One, two ♪ - ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ 一，二 ♪ - ♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪ - ♪ Hey! ♪
- ♪ 一，二，三，四！ ♪ - ♪ 嘿！ ♪
[cheerful music]
- Guess what day it is.
- 猜猜今天是什么日子。
- The day after our school was sunk?
- 我们学校沉没后的那一天？
- The worst day ever.
- 有史以来最糟糕的一天。
- Turds-day.
- 屎日。
- Turds-day? You mean Thursday.
- 屎日？你是说星期四。
- No.
- 不是。
- Turds-day. [laughs]
- 屎日。[笑]
- Well, I was going for Sunday.
- 嗯，我本来想说星期天的。
- Come on, have some ice cream. It'll cheer you up.
- 来吧，吃点冰淇淋。会让你开心起来的。
- How come you guys are so cheery?
- 你们怎么这么开心？
You loved the school too.
你也爱这所学校。
- Pff. Who actually loves their school?
- 哼，谁真的喜欢自己的学校？
[together] We did.
[一起] 我们喜欢。
- If the investigators ever find out what caused it--
- 如果调查人员发现是什么导致的——
- Or who-- - What do you mean?
- 或者是谁—— - 你什么意思？
There's no who. - Yeah, it's definitely a what.
没有谁。 - 是的，肯定是个什么。
- Totally a what. - What, what!
- 绝对是个什么。 - 什么，什么！
- You guys are acting werd.
- 你们表现得怪怪的。
- Well, you know, instead of thinking about the who
- 嗯，你知道，与其纠结是谁
and the what and the werd,
和是什么以及怪怪的，
let's focus on the where.
不如关注一下在哪里。
Like, where we're gonna be going to school.
比如，我们要去哪里上学。
Here--Boulder Academy.
这里——博尔德学院。
With its "unique classes, clubs,
拥有“独特的课程、社团，
"and brand new facilities
以及全新的设施
with state-of-the-art equipment."
配备最先进的设备。
Eh? - And all new students!
嗯？
It took us three months to finally be comfortable at the old school.
而且都是新生！
- And now we're back at square one.
我们花了三个月才在原来的学校感到自在。
- Well, we'll be at square two in no time.
现在我们又回到了起点。
I mean, come on, look at these
不过，我们很快就会到达第二阶段。
happy students with their smiling faces,
快乐的同学们，脸上洋溢着笑容，
all having a great time.
每个人都玩得很开心。
Those smiles are infectious.
那些笑容很有感染力。
- It looks like everyone is already friends at this place.
- 看起来这里的每个人都已经成了朋友。
- There's obvs no room for us.
- 显然没有我们的位置了。
- Calm down.
- 冷静点。
There's room for everyone.
每个人都有位置。
[gasps] Oh, no.
[倒吸一口气] 哦，不。
This school already has a kid with tiny green pants.
这所学校已经有一个穿小绿裤子的孩子了。
There's obvs no room for us!
显然没有我们的位置了！
- Okay, let's focus on the positive,
好吧，让我们关注积极的一面，
like this study buddy program.
比如这个学习伙伴计划。
- That started three months ago.
那是在三个月前开始的。
Which means everybody's study-buddied up.
这意味着每个人都已经有学习伙伴了。
- Relax. I'll be your spuddy buddy.
放松。我会成为你的学习伙伴。
- It's study buddy.
是学习伙伴。
- Oh yeah?
哦，是吗？
Then why do I have this potato?
那为什么我手里有个土豆？
- I don't know.
我不知道。
Hey, Dicky, getting a jump on your spuddying, huh?
嘿，迪基，已经开始你的学习伙伴计划了，是吧？
- What is happening?
这是怎么回事？
- What's happening is that you're nervous
你紧张是因为要去新学校。
about going to a new school.
但你已经在罗斯柴尔德预科交了朋友，
But you made friends at Rothschild Prep,
我相信你在这里也会交到朋友的。
and I'm sure you'll make friends here too.
是啊，你只要走到某人面前说些酷的话，
- Yeah, you just go up to somebody and say something cool,
比如，呃，“哥们儿，最近怎么样？”
like, uh, "What's good, big boy?"
对，或者，“美女，你看起来真棒。”
- Yeah, or, "Looking fly, girl."
哈哈，是吗？看，你们懂的。
- Haha, yeah? See, you guys get it.
是的。
- Yeah. - We get it.
我们懂了。
- Do you guys get it? [together] No.
你们明白了吗？[一起] 不明白。
- But they're right.
但他们是对的。
I mean, if we were able to fit in once,
我的意思是，如果我们曾经能够融入一次，
we should be able to do it again.
我们应该能够再次做到。
We just need to do the same thing
我们只需要在新学校的
on the first day of our new school
第一天做我们在上一所学校所做的事情。
as we did at our last school.
是的。我们一起穿过那些现在下沉的门...
- Yes. We entered through those now-sunken doors together...
一起。
- Together. - Full of confidence.
充满自信。
- Confidence!
自信！
- Laughing and acting like we belonged there.
笑着，表现得我们属于那里。
- There!
那里！
- We just need to make a good first impression, again.
我们只需要再次留下一个好印象。
- I guess that makes sense.
我想那是有道理的。
- Of course it makes sense.
当然有道理。
Here, we'll meet outside the new school at 8:12,
这里，我们将在新学校外8:12见面，
just like last time.
就像上次一样。
Who's in?
谁参加？
- I'm game. - I'm in.
我参加。
- Let's do it. - Hey, there's ice cream.
我们开始吧。嘿，有冰淇淋。
- Oh, Sundae.
- 哦，圣代。
- All right, then we'll see you guys tomorrow.
- 好吧，那我们明天见。
- All right, we'll see ya. - See ya.
- 好的，回见。
[overlapping chatter]
- 回见。
- At least they left here feeling hopeful
[重叠的谈话声]
about the new school
- 至少他们离开时对新学校满怀希望
and not thinking about who sunk the old school.
- 而不是想着是谁毁了旧学校。
- I almost forgot.
- 我差点忘了。
We have to figure out who sunk the old school.
- 我们还得找出是谁毁了旧学校。
Never forget! Rothschild forever!
- 永远不要忘记！罗斯柴尔德永远！
See you tomorrow at 8:12.
明天8点12分见。
- "Find out who sunk the old school?!"
- “找出是谁沉了旧学校？！”
- We sunk the old school!
- 是我们沉了旧学校！
- They're gonna find out we're the sinkers!
- 他们会发现是我们干的！
[smack] - Relax.
- [啪] - 放松。
- Well, the backhand's new.
- 嗯，反手是新的。
[smack]
- [啪]
- Yeah, that feels right.
- 是的，感觉对了。
- Once they get to the new school
- 一旦他们到了新学校
and make new friends, it'll blow over.
- 交了新朋友，这件事就会过去的。
Trust me, this will all be fixed by 8:13 tomorrow.
相信我，明天8点13分之前一切都会解决的。
- It's 8:13.
- 现在是8点13分。
- War are they?
- 他们在争论什么？
I wonder what the holdup is.
我想知道是什么耽搁了。
- ♪ We walk in the schoolyard all day long ♪
- ♪ 我们整天在学校操场上走 ♪
♪ Rockin' and a-boppin' just feelin' real calm ♪
♪ 摇摆着，跳跃着，感觉真的很平静 ♪
- Wrap it up.
- 结束吧。
- Hold on, I have to sing the whole song, just like last time!
- 等等，我得把整首歌唱完，就像上次一样！
- Well, sing it faster, or you're going to make us late!
- 好吧，唱快点，不然我们要迟到了！
- ♪ All the new kids at our great new school ♪
♪ 我们新学校里的所有新孩子 ♪
♪ Love to see the Quads look cool-cool-cool ♪ - Okay, I'm all good to go. - What do you have on your feet?
♪ 喜欢看四胞胎酷酷的样子 ♪ - 好了，我准备好了。 - 你脚上穿的是什么？
- My new kicks. Pretty fire, right?
- 我的新鞋。很炫酷吧？
- I don't know what that means,
- 我不懂那是什么意思，
but you wore orange shoes last time.
但你上次穿的是橙色鞋子。
- But these are more fire.
- 但这些更炫酷。
- I don't care if they're actually on fire.
- 我不在乎它们是不是真的着火了。
Stick to the formula.
坚持原来的搭配。
There is no time to lollygag.
没时间闲逛了。
- Ugh! Your breath is making me lollygag.
- 啊！你的口气让我想闲逛。
- Great. Now I've got nervous breath.
- 太好了。现在我紧张得喘不过气来。
- Socks or no socks? - Whatever you did last time.
- 穿袜子还是不穿袜子？ - 上次怎么做的就怎么做。
- Okay, one of each it is.
- 好吧，那就各穿一只。
- Why aren't your shoes on?
- 你的鞋子怎么没穿好？
- They're too tight. My feet must have grown.
- 鞋子太紧了。我的脚肯定长大了。
- Do you remember which foot was socked?
- 你记得哪只脚穿了袜子吗？
- Think it was the right one. - We're going to be late!
- 好像是右脚。 - 我们要迟到了！
- What happened to your shoes? They were fire.
- 你的鞋子怎么了？它们之前很棒的。
- Ricky put out my fire.
- 里奇熄灭了我的‘火’。
- Being late makes Ricky faint!
- 迟到会让里奇晕倒的！
Here we go.
我们走吧。
- Aaaand they're late.
- 他们迟到了。
- Welcome!
- 欢迎！
You must be some of the new kids from that poor school
你们一定是那所穷学校的几个新孩子
that, well, ya know...
那个，嗯，你们知道的...
[together] Pfftht!
[一起] 噗！
- [gasps]
- [吸气声]
We did not plan that.
我们没计划那样。
- We didn't.
- 我们没有。
- Hi, I'm Sadie. - And I'm Kipper.
- 嗨，我是Sadie。 - 我是Kipper。
It's short for Skipper.
这是Skipper的简称。
- And I'm Miles, short for Smiles.
- 我是Miles，Smiles的简称。
- Really?
- 真的吗？
I'm Dooley, m'lady.
我是Dooley，女士。
- Really? I'm Mae, and this is Avery.
- 真的吗？我是Mae，这是Avery。
- Cool har.
- 酷啊。
- I told you I'm not the only one
- 我告诉过你，我不是唯一一个
who talks like a pirate.
说话像海盗的人。
Har!
哈！
- No, har. Up thar.
- 不，是哈。上面那个。
- Oh. Thanks.
- 哦。谢谢。
- Sorry.
对不起。
He's just a little harrrd of hearing.
他只是有点耳背。
Ooh, that is fun!
哦，这真有趣！
- I told you!
我告诉过你！
- Why didn't I listen?
我为什么没听？
- 'Cause you're a scallywag.
因为你是个无赖。
- Come on, we'll show you landlubbers around.
来吧，我们会带你这个陆地人四处看看。
- Aye, aye, Captain!
遵命，船长！
Really? - This is awesome.
真的吗？这太棒了。
We already made new friends.
我们已经交了新朋友。
- Shouldn't we wait for the Quads?
- 我们不应该等四轮车吗？
- Ah, don't worry about them.
- 啊，别担心他们。
I'm sure they'll be arrre-right.
我确信他们会没事的。
Hey, that is fun.
嘿，这很有趣。
- You're a scallywag.
- 你是个捣蛋鬼。
- Mae, the friend ship is sailing.
- 梅，友谊之船正在航行。
- Where could they be?
- 他们会在哪儿呢？
- I knew you guys would make us late!
- 我就知道你们会让我们迟到！
- Us? You fainted.
- 我们？是你昏倒了。
- Maybe he smelled his own breath.
- 也许是他闻到了自己的口气。
- My breath was minty fresh
- 我的呼吸本来是薄荷般清新，
until your tardiness started making me nervous!
直到你的迟到开始让我紧张！
Well you must be terrified right now, 'cause wow.
那你现在一定吓坏了，因为哇。
- Guys! Stop it. Where are they?
- 伙计们！别闹了。他们在哪儿？
[flatulent noises]
[放屁声]
- What's with the shoe toots?
- 鞋子怎么回事？
- I buttered my feet so the shoes would fit.
- 我在脚上涂了黄油，所以鞋子能穿上。
- There they are!
- 他们在那儿！
- Do you think they went in without us?
- 你觉得他们会不等我们就进去了吗？
- Uh, yes. Yes, I do.
- 呃，是的。是的，我觉得会。
- Do you think they'll wait for us?
- 你觉得他们会等我们吗？
- Uh, no. No, I don't.
- 呃，不会。不，我不这么认为。
[rock music]
[摇滚音乐]
- Great. We wanted to make a good first impression,
- 太好了。我们本想留下一个好印象，
but instead we made no impression.
结果我们什么印象都没留下。
- Don't worry. As the saying goes,
- 别担心。俗话说，
you always get a second chance to make a first impression.
你总是有第二次机会来留下第一印象。
- That's not a saying.
- 那不是俗话。
- Mae just texted.
- Mae刚刚发了短信。
Looks like we're gonna get a second chance
看来我们会有第二次机会
to make a first impression.
给别人留下第一印象。
- Told you.
告诉你了吧。
- She said she's sorry they bailed on us,
她说她很抱歉他们放了我们鸽子，
but everyone's gathering in the common area right now.
但现在大家都在公共区域集合。
So let's just get in there.
所以我们直接进去吧。
- Great. Now remember, we stick to the formula.
很好。记住，我们要坚持我们的套路。
We go in confident and happy.
我们要自信且快乐地进去。
- Big Boy the Wolverine.
大男孩，金刚狼。
Not only our school mascot,
不仅是我们的校徽，
but also our furry friend.
也是我们毛茸茸的朋友。
- And now a moment of silence.
— 现在请安静片刻。
[door flings open]
[门猛地打开]
- Hey, Boulder Academy!
— 嘿，博尔德学院！
- Harpers in the house! - Woot-woot!
— 哈珀一家来了！— 哇哦！
- What's good, big boy?!
— 怎么样，大兄弟？！
- Hey, guys.
— 嘿，大家。
- Jeez. Who died?
— 天哪，谁去世了？
- Big Boy did.
— 大男孩没了。
[together] Ohhh.
[齐声] 哦～
- Uh... can we all just pretend this never happened?
— 呃……我们能假装这一切都没发生过吗？
- We were never here.
- 我们从未在这里。
[flatulent noises] - And you never heard that.
- 而且你从未听到过那个。
Or that.
- 或者那个。
[prrff]
- 还有那个。
Or that.
- 或者那个。
- Would you take your shoes off?
- 你能把鞋脱了吗？
- It's not my shoes.
- 不是我的鞋。
I get nervous breath in a different place.
- 我在不同的地方紧张呼吸。
[prrff]
- 还有那个。
- Today was a complete disaster.
- 今天完全是一场灾难。
We ruined any chance we had of making a good first impression.
我们毁掉了留下好第一印象的任何机会。
- At least our friends have friends.
至少我们的朋友有朋友。
- Kids, if you're having trouble making friends,
孩子们，如果你们在交朋友方面有困难，
maybe you should join a club.
也许你们应该加入一个俱乐部。
- Yes! That's just the ticket.
是的！那正是我们需要的。
- Just the ticket?
正是我们需要的？
That's not a saying, Dad.
那不是一句俗语，爸爸。
- Okay, you know what is a saying?
好吧，你知道什么是一句俗语吗？
"What up, club peeps!
"嗨，俱乐部的朋友们！
Harpers ready to get they club on!"
哈珀准备好加入俱乐部了！"
See, that is what you can say when you join.
看，这就是你加入时可以说的话。
They'll love it.
他们会喜欢的。
- Let's say they do.
- 就算他们喜欢。
Is that a club we really want to be in?
这是我们真正想加入的俱乐部吗？
- Sorry, Mom. We're just not club people.
- 对不起，妈妈。我们真的不是那种喜欢俱乐部的人。
- Hey, guys.
- 嘿，伙计们。
Kipper and Sadie invited us to join the Mystery Solvers Club,
Kipper和Sadie邀请我们加入神秘解谜俱乐部，
and we convinced them to let you in, too.
我们还说服他们让你也加入。
- Ooh, a club? We are totally club people.
- 哦，一个俱乐部？我们绝对是那种喜欢俱乐部的人。
- Harpers ready to get they club on!
- Harpers准备好加入俱乐部了！
- Yeah. Maybe don't say that over there.
是啊。也许那边不要这么说。
- The club's a great idea.
这个俱乐部是个好主意。
It's just the ticket.
正是我们需要的。
- Just the ticket. That's a great saying.
正是我们需要的。这是个很好的说法。
- But when I said it, you said it wasn't a saying.
但当我这么说时，你说这不是个说法。
- Well when you said it, it wasn't.
嗯，当你说的时候，它还不是。
- You know what, it looks like we are not appreciated
你知道吗，看来我们在这里不受赏识。
around here.
走吧，汤姆。
Come on, Tom. - Right behind you, fly girl.
就在你后面，飞女孩。
We'll catch you on the backside, and that is a saying.
我们会在后面抓住你，那是个说法。
- It's flipside. - Dang it!
- 是反面。 - 该死！
- Guys, this is Sadie and Kipper.
- 伙计们，这是Sadie和Kipper。
- As the president of the Mystery Solvers Club,
- 作为Mystery Solvers Club的主席，
I'd like to say welcome.
我想表示欢迎。
- And as the vice president of the Mystery Solvers Club,
- 而作为Mystery Solvers Club的副主席，
I'd like to say what an amazing job you're doing as president.
我想说你作为主席做得非常出色。
- No, you're doing an amazing job.
- 不，你做得非常出色。
- No, you are. - No, you are.
- 不，是你。 - 不，是你。
Anyway. Welcome, welcome. Sit sit.
总之。欢迎欢迎。坐坐。
- So, Mystery Solvers Club, huh?
- 那么，Mystery Solvers Club，是吗？
- Yup, they solve real mysteries around the school.
是的，他们在学校周围解决真实的谜团。
Like "The Case of the Stolen School Supplies."
比如“失窃的学校用品案”。
- Turns out it was the janitor. [together] Oooooh.
结果是清洁工干的。
- And "The Case of the Half-Eaten Party Sub."
还有“被吃了一半的派对三明治案”。
- Also the janitor. [together] Aaaahh.
也是清洁工。
- So, what's our case gonna be?
那么，我们的案件会是什么呢？
- "The Case of Who Sunk Rothschild Prep."
“谁沉没了罗斯柴尔德预备学校案”。
- Starting tomorrow,
从明天开始，
we roll up our sleeves and start digging for facts.
我们卷起袖子，开始挖掘事实。
We will not rest until the sinkers are brought to justice.
我们不会休息，直到那些沉没者受到正义的制裁。
Never forget. Rothschild forever!
永远不要忘记。罗斯柴尔德永存！
all: Yeah!
大家：耶！
- I think we're all thinking the same thing here, right?
- 我想我们大家在这里都在想同一件事，对吧？
- How annoying Mae is with that "Never forget.
- 梅有多烦人，总是说“永远不要忘记。
Rothschild Forever!"?
罗斯柴尔德永存！”？
- How obvious it is that Sadie and Kipper love each other
- 赛迪和基珀彼此相爱
but lack the courage to admit it?
却缺乏勇气承认这一点有多明显？
- How I shouldn't have eaten that string cheese
- 我不应该吃昨天在地上找到的那根干酪？
I found on the ground yesterday?
- 不。
- No.
嗯，是的。这三件事都是。
Well, yes. All three of those.
But more importantly,
但更重要的是，
if we don't throw them off our trail,
如果我们不甩掉他们，
we're going down faster than that school we sank.
我们就会比我们沉没的那所学校还要快地沉下去。
- My nervous breath is back.
- 我的紧张呼吸又回来了。
Here we go again.
我们又要开始了。
- I knew it was his breath.
- 我就知道是他的呼吸。
- ♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ 啦，啦，啦，啦，啦 ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
[indistinct chatter]
[听不清的交谈声]
- Okay. That's them!
- 好了，就是他们！
Everybody stick to the plan.
大家都按计划行事。
Hey guys! - Wow. You're a busy bunch.
嘿，伙计们！- 哇，你们真是忙忙碌碌的一群人。
- What is all this?
- 这都是些什么？
- Oh, we just wanted to get a jump on the case.
- 哦，我们只是想早点开始这个案件。
- We started by brainstorming for three hours
- 我们从集思广益了三个小时开始，
and came up with the one question
并提出了那个无人能想到要问的问题:
that no one else would think to ask:
“是谁干的？”
"Who did it?"
- 这些家伙不搞虚的。
- These guys don't mess around.
- 是...普拉塔库斯先生，那个手工课老师吗？
- Was it...
- 是……
Mr. Platakus, the shop teacher?
普拉塔库斯先生，那位商店老师？
- [gasps] Platakus did it?
- [吸气声] 普拉塔库斯干的？
- No.
- 不。
But we did find out it's pronounced "Pla-two-cuss."
但我们确实发现它的发音是“Pla-two-cuss”。
- Why does that matter?
- 这有什么关系？
- It doesn't. Just FYI.
- 没关系。只是顺便一提。
- So we moved on to our next suspect...
- 于是我们转向了下一个嫌疑人……
Mr. Faubus, the bus driver!
福布斯先生，那位公交车司机！
- He did it?
- 是他干的？
- No. But we did find out it's actually Mrs. Faubus.
- 不，但我们确实发现实际上是Faubus夫人。
- To be fair, the mustache kinda threw us.
- 公平地说，那胡子确实让我们迷惑了。
- And since she didn't do it,
- 既然她没有做，
we moved on to our next, next suspect...
我们就转向了下一个，再下一个嫌疑人...
- We don't care who didn't do it.
- 我们不在乎谁没做。
Can we just get to what's behind the big question mark?
我们能直接讨论那个大问号背后的内容吗？
- Fine.
- 好的。
- Now what's behind that question mark?
- 那么，那个问号背后是什么？
- How many question marks are there?
- 有多少个问号？
- I'll ask the questions around here.
- 这里的问题由我来问。
How many question marks are there?
有多少个问号？
- I'll ask the questions around here.
我会在这一带问问题。
How many question marks are there?
有多少个问号？
- I will ask the questions around here.
我会在这一带问问题。
Exactly how many--
到底有多少个——
- Do you guys know who did it or not?!
你们知道是谁干的吗？！
- Not. Which proves one thing:
不知道。这证明了一件事：
this case is unsolvable.
这个案件是无解的。
Who wants donuts?
谁想要甜甜圈？
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no. No case is unsolvable.
哦，不，不，不，不，不，不。没有案件是无解的。
- We're Mystery Solvers, not Mystery Quitters.
- 我们是谜题解决者，不是谜题放弃者。
- But since this case seems impossible,
- 但是既然这个案子看起来不可能解决，
can't we move on to a different case? Like...
我们能不能换个案子？比如...
I don't know, um,
我不知道，嗯，
oh, who was behind Big Boy's demise?
哦，是谁导致了大男孩的死亡？
- Great! Dawn just saved us.
- 太好了！Dawn刚刚救了我们。
- Well actually, it's the same case.
- 实际上，这是同一个案子。
We think toxic gas from the sinkhole
我们认为是从那个地陷处泄漏的有毒气体
was what spelled the end for Big Boy,
导致了Big Boy的死亡，
so find the sinkers, find the killers!
所以找到地陷的原因，就能找到凶手！
- Great. Dawn just sank us.
- 太好了。Dawn刚刚让我们陷入了困境。
- So tomorrow we go back to Rothschild Prep
- 所以明天我们回到Rothschild预备学校
and look for clues.
寻找线索。
- I love it!
- 我喜欢这个主意！
- Will you excuse us for one minute?
- 你能让我们离开一会儿吗？
Clues! If they go there, they'll find our gardening gloves!
线索！如果他们去那里，他们会找到我们的园艺手套！
They have our names on them!
上面有我们的名字！
- You just had to take that stupid embroidery class,
- 你当时非得参加那个愚蠢的刺绣课，
didn't you?
对吧？
- Uh, hello?
- 呃，你好？
So we'll meet tomorrow morning at the scene of the crime
所以我们明天早上在犯罪现场见面
to figure out who's responsible for everything.
来弄清楚这一切是谁的责任。
- You guys are in, right?
- 你们都会来，对吧？
[all stammering] - Yup.
[大家都结巴了] - 是的。
We'll be there, bright and early.
我们会早早到那里的。
See you tomorrow. - Bye.
明天见。 - 再见。
- Bye, guys. See you tomorrow.
- 再见，大家。明天见。
- We get rid of those gloves and pin this on somebody else.
- 我们把那些手套处理掉，然后栽赃给别人。
- So when you say "get rid of those gloves,"
- 所以当你说“处理掉那些手套”，
you mean take, not throw away.
你是说拿走，不是扔掉。
I mean, I spent a lot of time on those.
我的意思是，我在那些手套上花了很多时间。
- You know those were in a stinkhole, right?
- 你知道那些手套是在一个臭水坑里的，对吧？
- You know how hard a lazy daisy stitch is, right?
- 你知道一个懒散的雏菊针脚有多难，对吧？
It's much harder than it sounds.
这比听起来要难得多。
♪ ♪
- So who are we gonna pin this on?
- 那我们打算把这件事推给谁？
- Big Boy!
- 大块头！
I mean, they think the sinkhole's fumes
我的意思是，他们认为那个污水坑的气味导致了他的死亡。
caused his demise.
那如果他是因为在那里才吸入那些气味的呢？
Well what if he breathed in the fumes because he was there?
如果大块头是整个事件的背后主谋呢？
What if Big Boy was behind the entire thing?
如果整件事都是大块头在背后操纵的呢？
- Yes! We'll frame Big Boy.
- 对！我们就把罪名推给大块头。
- But like, how do we sell this?
- 但是，我们怎么让人相信呢？
Uh, we'd have to cover the place with wolverine paw prints.
呃，我们得在这地方弄上狼獾的爪印。
- Where are we going to find a wolverine
- 我们去哪儿找愿意帮忙的狼獾？
willing to help us do that?
- 也许我们可以利用大块头的雕像。
- Maybe we can use the Big Boy statue.
- 或者我可以直接去森林里
- Or I could just go into the woods
抓一只真正的狼獾。
and catch a real wolverine.
它们很友好，对吧？
They're friendly, right?
不友好。就用雕像吧。
Not friendly. Statue it is.
不友好。那就用雕像吧。
- ♪♪
- Wolverine, wolverine, wolverine...
- 金刚狼，金刚狼，金刚狼...
Wolverine!
金刚狼！
- Wolverines don't say "wolverine."
- 金刚狼不会说“金刚狼”。
- Then what do they say? - Just hurry up.
- 那它们说什么？ - 快点。
- Just hurry up, just hurry up, just hurry up...
- 快点，快点，快点...
- Just make it look like Big Boy walked over to the pipe,
- 就让它看起来像大男孩走到管子那里，
clawed it open, and walked out.
用爪子打开，然后走出去。
I'll get rid of our gloves.
我会处理掉我们的手套。
- Uh-oh.
- 哎呀。
The Mystery Solvers are coming.
神秘解谜者来了。
The Mystery Solvers are coming!
神秘解谜者来了！
- Okay, ditch Big Boy! And the gloves!
- 快，丢掉大男孩！还有手套！
Hurry, guys!
快点，伙计们！
[gasps] Uh-oh! - The pipe's leaking!
[喘气] 哎呀！ - 管道漏了！
- It must be because we took our gloves out!
- 一定是因为我们把手套拿出来了！
- Apply pressure! Stand on it!
- 施加压力！踩上去！
- Hey, what's up, club peeps?
- 嘿，俱乐部的朋友们，怎么了？
- You're here early.
- 你来早了。
- That's real Mystery Solver spirit.
- Yep. - Solving mysteries.
- Nose to the grindstone. - Early bird gets the bacon.
- Dude, are you wearing a diaper?
- Yes, yes I am.
That's how dedicated I am to solving this crime.
I won't leave here for any reason.
- Okay.
- Speaking of, we found some evidence.
[grunts]
Which is way over there. Look!
那东西在那边很远的地方。看！
- War?
战争？
- Um, way over thar.
嗯，在那边很远的地方。
Out the dar.
在那边。
You know, just keep going.
你知道的，继续走。
You'll see it.
你会看到的。
Little mar.
小湖。
I need something to plug this hole.
我需要东西来堵住这个洞。
- Uh, Dicky, what about your spuddy buddy?
呃，迪基，你的土豆伙伴怎么样？
- Channing Tater? No way!
查宁·塔特？不可能！
- Just give him to me.
- 把他给我吧。
- Yo, bro-tato. Be safe.
- 哥们薯条，保重啊。
- We don't see anything out here!
- 我们在外面什么也没看到！
- Keep looking!
- 继续找！
- Channing, no!
- 钱宁，不行！
- There's nothing out there.
- 外面什么都没有。
- Psh, and you call yourselves Mystery Solvers.
- 哼，你们还自称神秘解谜者呢。
I mean, there are clearly wolverine paw prints
我意思是，这里明显有狼獾的爪印
leading to a pipe that was sliced open
通向一条被利爪割开的管道。
by razor-sharp claws.
只能得出结论，罪魁祸首就是大男孩！
One can only conclude
只能得出一个结论
that the culprit was Big Boy!
那就是罪魁祸首是Big Boy！
[together] Big Boy?
[一起] Big Boy？
- Yep, mystery solved.
- 是的，谜团解开了。
You can all go now.
你们现在都可以走了。
- Wait, why are you sitting in a bucket?
- 等等，你为什么坐在桶里？
- You know, I could ask you the same thing.
- 你知道，我也可以问你同样的问题。
- No you can't, 'cause I'm not sitting in a bucket.
- 不，你不能，因为我没有坐在桶里。
- Okay, I think it's obvious what's going on here.
- 好吧，我认为这里的情况很明显。
- These wolverine prints are fake
- 这些狼獾的脚印是假的
and you're covering for the real guilty party.
而且你是在为真正的罪犯打掩护。
- The truth is...
真相是...
the Quads are guilty!
Quad组是罪魁祸首！
[all gasp]
（所有人惊呼）
- Of covering for you four!
他们是在为你们四个人掩盖！
[together] What?!
什么？！
- I thought we were friends.
我以为我们是朋友。
But how can we be friends after this?
但经过这件事后，我们怎么还能做朋友呢？
- We're gonna tell the whole school what you did,
我们要告诉全校你们做了什么，
and nobody's gonna want to be friends with you.
没人会想和你们做朋友了。
- No, it wasn't them.
- 不，不是他们。
[sighs deeply]
[深叹一口气]
It was us.
是我们。
both: What?
什么？
- It's true. We sunk the school.
- 这是真的。我们弄沉了学校。
- But it was an accident.
- 但那是个意外。
- And we're sorry.
- 我们很抱歉。
- And scene!
- 停！
- Wait, w-what's going on?
- 等等，这-这是怎么回事？
- Surprise! There is no Mystery Solvers Club.
- 惊喜！根本没有什么解谜俱乐部。
- We're all in the Drama Club.
我们都是戏剧俱乐部的成员。
[all gasp]
（所有人惊讶）
- Why would you do this?
你们为什么要这么做？
- Well, once we saw how weird you acted after the school sank,
嗯，自从我们发现你在学校沉没后行为变得很奇怪，
with all your giving us free ice cream, and your "what-what's,"
又是请我们吃免费冰淇淋，又是说那些‘什么什么’的，
we thought you might've had something to do with it.
我们就怀疑你可能与此事有关。
- And since you obviously weren't going to
既然你显然不打算
tell us the truth...
告诉我们真相……
- We had to find a way to get you to admit it.
我们不得不想办法让你承认。
- So you could spend less time keeping secrets
这样你就可以少花时间保守秘密
and more time making new friends.
并且有更多时间结交新朋友。
- Well, thank you.
嗯，谢谢你。
How about we start now?
我们现在就开始怎么样？
[grunts]
哼。
If you don't mind,
如果你不介意，
we would really like a third chance
我们真的很想再有一次机会
to make our first impression.
来留下我们的第一印象。
- Oh, it's way too late for that.
哦，那已经太晚了。
But it's never too late to make a new friend.
但结交新朋友永远不会太晚。
- So you forgive us for sending Big Boy
所以你原谅我们派大块头
to the great big wolverine den in the sky?
把它送到天上的大狼獾窝里？
- Oh, you guys didn't kill our wolverine.
- 哦，你们并没有杀死我们的狼獾。
He died of old age.
他是老死的。
- But is that our Big Boy statue?
- 但那是我们的巨型狼獾雕像吗？
- You stole our statue?!
- 你们偷了我们的雕像？！
- From our new friends. You guys.
- 从我们的新朋友那里。你们。
We're losing them.
我们正在失去他们。
- I really wish we had a way out of this one.
- 我真的希望我们能找到摆脱这个困境的方法。
[blasting]
[爆炸声]
- We found a waaaayyyyyyy!
- 我们找到了一个出路！
- Good thing he was wearing a diaper, huh?
- 幸好他穿了尿布，是吧？
- ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
[whistling]
♪ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
- ♪ 耶！ ♪